# Stephen Kent

## Backend Software Developer

♀ 2700 Dorr Ave, VA 22031, Fairfax (US)

stevekcode@gmail.com

**(571) 295-6530** 

O stevejkcode in linkedin html pdf

I'm a backend web developer with several years of experience developing, maintaining, and managing cloud native web applications. In addition to implementation I have been responsible for driving the full development lifecycle, from design through to deployment, maintenance and operations and I am comfortable handling the demands of modern software projects. In my spare time I'm usually playing guitar (badly) or learning French.

### Experience

#### Capital One March 2016 - February 2023

#### Mid Backend Developer

Developed Cyber Security solutions to enable developers to build secure software early in the development lifecycle.

- Led architecture and design efforts for critical software components
- Designed and implemented core REST APIs via Express.js
- Wrote unit tests in Mocha.js
- Reviewed and mentored the work of Junior developers
- Wrote AWS Lambda functions in JavaScript and Python - Designed and implemented distributed work queue systems with AWS SQS as well as Bull.is (similar to Celery)
- Wrote disaster recovery plans and carried them out during internal exercises
- Designed data models and indexing strategies in MongoDB and DynamoDB
- Met with stake holders to gather requirements and report project status
- Led Agile ceremonies such as sprint planning and review when needed
- Co-authored US Patent No. 10,387,659 for the de-duplication of static source code security findings

## **CFPB**

#### November 2014 - December 2015

#### Jr. Backend Developer

Built tools to facilitate consumer protections and regulatory oversight.

- Developed flexible software components in JavaScript
- Designed JSON schemas for defining linting rules
- Wrote unit tests in Mocha.is
- Developed REST APIs for querying against public data (Census, etc) via Express.js
- Wrote queries for MongoDB via Mongoose

## FCC

## March 2014 - November 2014

## Jr. Backend Developer

Developed backend Python code for aggregating and displaying cellular internet performance testing results.

- Developed primary Python software components, including daily statistics aggregation
- Worked with stake holders to gather requirements and ensure the process was able to meet stringent regulations, especially regarding user privacy - Designed and published maps using Tilemill
- Designed data models in Mongo for storing aggregate statistics
- Performed geospacial queries in MongoDB for bucketing results

## Certifications

#### **AWS Solutions Architect Associate** March 2022

Issued by Amazon

Link

### Education

## University of Maryland

Bachelors

#### Computer Engineering

Backend Development			Database			REST APIs			Cloud						
Senior			Senior			Mid			Jr						
JavaScript	NodeJS	Python	MongoDB	DynamoDB	PostgreSQL	Express	Swagger	Flask	AWS	IAM	VPC	EC2	S3	sqs	Lambda
Devops Jr				Project Management Mid											

EasyVocab July 2022 - August 2022

Projects

https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/203110167

EasyVocab is an Anki plugin I wrote to enable easy and automatic generation of flashcards for foreign language vocabulary study.

Users can input a list of words they would like to study and EasyVocab will use Google Translate to automatically generate beautiful flash cards. Google TTS is also utilized to create audio pronunciation for each word, and reverse cards which have English on the front and the user's target language on the back can also be created to help develop a two way association the words in both languages.